Now this is an open front winter turnout blanket.
Let me show you the easiest way to take on and off a winter horse blanket.
First to take it off, this is Rudy, he's already got it on, unbuckle the front and this also has a Velcro behind it so we will undo that as well.
Then he is going to have three surcingles and we are going to undo those three surcingles and then this blanket also has the tail strap and we are going to take that off as well.
A turnout open front blanket is really easy.
We just slide it right off the side.
Easy, just like that.
Now to put it back on, when you are putting on your horse blanket, obviously you want to make sure that your horse has been brushed.
It is just like before you put a saddle on.
If you put a blanket on and there is dirt underneath the blanket, it is just going to rub on your horse all the time so it is important to make sure that your horse is brushed off.
The open front is very easy to slide on.
All we need to do is just over the horse and again, just buckle him up.
So we will start in the front, do his chest straps, he has three belly surcingle that we will do next.
And last but not least on this blanket a ham strap.
So that is how to take on and off an open front blanket.